hey everyone welcome to another lesson
in this task automation course
so today
we are going to see
what is the tosca commander will see a
high level overview of all the different
modules which are present in the tosca
commander and we'll see how you can run
a example test case or test project
we'll also see how you can
start automating your web application
using the tosca commander so we'll do a
sample test case right
now uh we have already seen how we can
set up tosca commander with its license
in our last video so if not watched it
uh do watch it over
now once you launch your toska commander
this is the home page which will be
visible to you
there you will have some default
projects right
so the first steps project it is
provided by default to you by tosca
right so it contains some sample test
cases uh which you can run and get
acquainted with the tosca commander
so um right now we'll just open this uh
project which is already provided by the
toska commander so click on first steps
and it will start building your or
opening your project right
now this is the tosca commander
view you can say
the tool or the application
through which you can automate your test
cases right so there are different
uh sections to this particular
application or tool right
and
all of these different blocks which you
see here are all the different
parts of this tosca commander right so
these are the places where you will find
all the different um
information which you require in order
to automate your application right so
it completely supports the whole testing
life cycle right so the first thing
which you will notice is the test cases
section okay and this will contain all
your test cases okay so uh these test
cases are already provided uh
to us by the tosca right by default
and as you can see they have provided
some manual tests uh some automated
tests uh data driven tests
and some helpers right and they have
also given us this run me okay so this
is the sample test case which you can
run in this particular test cases
section okay
now there are other sections like
modules uh requirements test case design
execution
issues
right and there is also a tutorial but
that's not so important one okay
now um we will see what are modules what
are requirements test case design
and execution right uh throughout this
course whenever we're trying to build a
complete project okay for now let's
concentrate on this test cases section
okay so as you can see uh there are
different folders which you can create
for your test cases so that could be a
parent folder under that uh that could
be uh child folders and under each
folder you will have a test case right
like this and then that test case will
have different steps okay
so uh you can add your own folder you
can see create folder there is create
folder option you can create a folder
structure um you can create a virtual
folder we'll talk about it um later
uh you can create a test case right so
this um
circle symbol is a test case symbol okay
so this means this
is contains a test case okay
uh then there is a business test case uh
we'll talk about it later you can create
a step library right so there are
different options uh you can also create
recovery scenario collection and test
configuration parameters so there are
lots of things in tosca and we'll learn
um one by one slowly okay
so let's look at our test case okay so
these are the different steps uh these
are basically
you can call the steps which control the
execution of your application flow okay
for this particular test case
so as you can see there are different
steps like open sample app maximize the
browser main menu
vehicle data insurance data product data
price option and then send code so this
is a complete flow for your test case in
your application okay and what taos cut
does it it captures all the technical
information which are nothing but the
objects on the page which are required
to automate each and every flow of your
particular application right and once it
captures it provides it in this
particular test steps where you can
control what you want to enter in any or
any field to build your application or
test case flow okay
so when you are viewing this particular
test case you can do you can expand all
the steps you can collapse all the steps
right so as there are different steps i
can expand them and as you can see there
are different objects which are present
here right and each object or
each particular information right it
contains some data and it contains some
properties okay so as you can see this
automobile object it must be a input
uh input field right and um either you
can uh enter some information or you can
click on it right it could be a link
okay and that could be identified by
properties which is shown on the right
hand side right so using this properties
it can identify this particular object
on the page and then you can perform
some action on this particular object by
passing some value here okay so that is
how you build your test case or test
steps right similarly you will see there
are different fields where there are
different values for those fields right
so this is this is all uh the data which
you require for this particular test
case with all the fields right which are
available here
and that is how you control the flow of
your execution so depending on how your
test case is built you will enter those
values or
perform the operation on those fields
required in this particular test case
right now the initial two steps you can
see uh are just opening the sample
application and maximizing the browser
right and there you are passing the url
okay
similarly uh there would be also a test
configuration right
so these are the test case details and
the next step is test configuration now
it is also important um because you can
see here
this particular test case has got a test
configuration called browser right and
that browser is internet explorer okay
so that's the value you need to set in
order to run this test case on a
particular browser
now we can also change the test
configuration parameter value in this
case it is browser so you can put any
value for this right now the default
isn't in the explorer that's where the
test case was designed right so probably
you will try to run it in the same
browser but if you want to run your test
case on other browsers like chrome edge
firefox you can select those values okay
similarly you can add any number of test
configuration parameters by just right
clicking on the test case and then
clicking on this purple square button
which is for adding
a different test configuration parameter
for your test case okay so this is how
you can add different test configuration
parameters
okay uh let's reset to default value
and now we have seen what uh are the
details of our test cases what are test
configuration parameters and now
we'll look at the control flow diagram
right so this is a simple uh
representational view of your test case
right so the complete flow of the test
case with all the different steps which
are involved here okay
now that we have a good view of um how
we can design our test case um what
values we can pass what is the test
configuration parameter right
let's see how we can run our test case
so for that you can go to the test case
and then right click there's an option
run in scratch book that option is also
available on the top sidebar right under
test cases you can see a green play
button which is run in scratch book so
if you go ahead and select your test
case and then
run your test case
using the run in scratch book it will
start running your test case on the
application so as you can see it has
performed all the different actions on
the particular application right
now once it is finished you can go back
here and you can see this is the scratch
book right
so uh in scratch book you can do some
dry run testing of your test case okay
so if you want to check whether your
test case is working fine
or not or you have any issues then you
can use this run in scratch book
the only thing to remember is it's not
permanently stored right so these
results are not stored anywhere it is
only on a temporary basis right so for
uh storing results and all you need to
run it from a different place okay
so as you can see uh it will display all
the different steps it has performed
right which has passed and which has
failed inside this scratch book okay and
that start time and duration also if
you're logging any information or
message it will show it in the log info
right so this is your scratch book
now
as i said uh this is only
it only stores temporary results right
if you want to
store your results uh permanently or on
a permanent basis you need to execute
your test from the execution folder okay
so there you need to create an execution
list and then you need to create your
execution folder and then
bring your test cases here and start
execution okay
so that's how you can
run an existing test case from your
project in tosca right so this
particular test case was provided by
tosca but in our next session we'll be
looking at how we can design our own
test case okay how we can automate a
particular application using tosca and
that is when i am going to introduce you
to some of the other folders like
modules right how do you
um store all the technical information
in the modules folder and then use it in
your test cases right we'll also try to
see how we can execute our particular
test case from the execution folder
right
so uh slowly we'll also learn about
requirements uh and test case design and
how it can be linked to different test
cases and modules right